Finding Aid for Bennett Weaver papers, 1917-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bennett Weaver papers 1917-1969
Weaver, Bennett, 1892-1970.
1 linear foot
85457 Aa 2
Professor of English at the University of Michigan. Correspondence; lectures and speeches; and miscellaneous articles, essays, and poems.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Greg May (donor no. 6416 ) and came to the library in 1969.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Bennett Weaver was born in Sussex, Wisconsin on August 11, 1892. He received his A.B. degree from Carroll College, his M.A. from the University of Chicago, and his Ph.D. from the University of Michigan. He taught speech and English, first at Emporia College, then Michigan State College. In 1928, he came to the University of Michigan, teaching there until his retirement as emeritus professor. From 1966 to 1970, he was professor of English at the University of California, Irvine. His specialty was poetry. He died March 1, 1970.
The Bennett Weaver collection is comprised of three series: Correspondence; Lectures, speeches, and addresses; and Miscellaneous. Most of the lectures and speeches concern Anglo-American poetry, the Bible as literature, and patriotic themes.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of English Language and Literature.; University of Michigan--Faculty.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Weaver, Bennett, 1892-1970.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence, 1917-1969
  - Undated, 1917, 1929 and 1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1962 (Box 1)
  - 1963-1969 (Box 1)
  - Letters addressed to Robert Hellenga, 1961-1966 (Box 1)
- Lectures, speeches, and addresses, 1917-1966
  - Titled lecture series [arranged chronologically]
    - People's Church, East Lansing, 1922-1925 (Box 1)
    - Eliot/NIAE lectures, 1933-1934 and 1935-1936 (Box 1)
    - Pi Omicron series, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
    - Weaver lecture course, March 18-December 17, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Weaver lecture course, 1936 (Box 1)
      (nos. 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 8)
    - Round tables, Woodward Congregational Church, Detroit, October-November 1940 (Box 1)
    - Rackham Extension
      - October 1946-January 1947 (Box 1)
      - February-March 1947 (Box 1)
      - April-May 1947 (Box 1)
        (nos. 11 and 13 missing)
    - World Literature radio broadcast, September 1949-January 1950, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - "Browning at Lagunna," 1963 (Box 1)
    - "Ten Lectures at Ten," March-May 1963 (incomplete) (Box 1)
    - PEO series, May-July 1963 (Box 1)
    - "Keats and the Moderns," January-March 1965 (Box 1)
  - Lenten Lecture Series, February-March 1966 (Box 1)
    (nos. 3 and 4 missing)
  - Topical speech files
    - Religious talks, 1932-1939 (Box 1)
    - Religious talks, 194o-1947 (Box 1)
    - Patriotic and Political talks, 1935-1958 (Box 1)
    - Commencement and honors assembly addresses, 1939-1955 (Box 1)
    - Rotary Club Speeches, 1949, 1952, 1954, 1957 and 1961 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous speeches [arranged chronologically]
    - Undated (Box 1)
    - Undated, 1917, 1923 (Box 1)
    - 1933-1934, 1936 (Box 1)
    - 1938 and 1939 (Box 1)
    - 1940 and 1941 (Box 1)
    - 1944 and 1949 (Box 1)
    - 1950-1958 (Box 1)
    - 1961-1967 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Biographical materials (Box 1)
  - Programs and announcements
    - Undated and 1934-1944 (Box 1)
    - 1945-1968 (Box 1)
  - Articles and Essays (Box 1)
  - Poems and other writings (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Photographs of family (Box 1)